Finding Aid for the C. F. Peters Collection of Morton Feldman Manuscripts, 1961-1969
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
C. F. Peters Collection of Morton Feldman Manuscripts, 1961-1969
Mus. Arc. 2.4
Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987
3 boxes (79 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection consists of 79 works by Morton Feldman in either score or part formats (72 scores; 7 sets of parts). All but one item are ink manuscripts on vellum. These served as the masters that Feldman submitted to C. F. Peters and Peters published directly from these masters. Almost all of the manuscripts are in Morton Feldman's hand, except for two scores copied by John Cage and three items in the hand of a music copyist.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from C. F. Peters, 2003.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Composer Morton Feldman (1926-1987) was best known for his association with the New York School of experimentalist musicians, including composers John Cage, Christian Wolff, and Earle Brown, and pianist David Tudor. In addition to composing approximately 150 works, Feldman also wrote more than three dozen articles about various aspects of music and art.
Feldman was a member of the music department faculty at the State University of New York at Buffalo 1972-1987. During those years he served as Slee Professor of Music 1972-1973, Edgar Varèse Professor 1975-1987, and Director of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts, 1976-1980. He was also responsible for creating the June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music in 1975.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 79 works by Morton Feldman in either score or part formats (72 scores; 7 sets of parts). All but one item are ink manuscripts on vellum. These served as the masters that Feldman submitted to C. F. Peters and Peters published directly from these masters. Almost all of the manuscripts are in Morton Feldman's hand, except for two scores copied by John Cage and three items in the hand of a music copyist. Some items are accompanied by the folders in which they were housed at C. F. Peters. The folders contain brief information about number of copies created and instructions for printing parts. As such, the collection provides a history of the music publishing process rather than anything about the musical genesis of the works. The original manuscripts for the works in the collection, if extant, are housed in the Paul Sacher Stiftung in Basel, Switzerland.
Arrangement
Compositions by Morton Feldman. Arranged in numerical order by C. F. Peters publisher numbers.
Container List
- Compositions by Morton Feldman, 1961-1969, I.; Items 1-79
  Arranged in numerical order by C. F. Peters publisher numbers.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Durations, no. 1 Durations I c1961., 1 ms. score (5 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 01)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For flute, violin, violoncello, and piano. At end of score: June 1960. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright assigned in 1962 to C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. C.F. Peters publisher's number, 6901, written in pencil bottom of leaf 1.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Durations, no. 2 Durations 2 c1961., 1 ms. score (2 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 02)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For violoncello and piano. At end of score: 2.2.60. "Copyright assigned in 1962 to C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6902 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Durations, no. 3 Durations 3: for violin, tuba, piano c1961., 1 ms. score (6 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 03)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. Notation does not indicate durations. At end of score: 2.16.61. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright assigned in 1962 to C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6903 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Durations, no. 4 Durations 4 1962., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 04)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For violin, violoncello, and vibraphone. "Copyright assigned in 1962 to C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Includes typescript instructions for performance (1 leaf; 28 cm.), with two copies printed in reverse. Assigned publisher's number 6904 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Durations, no. 5 Durations 5 c1962., 1 ms. score (8 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 05)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For horn, celesta and piano (1 player), harp, vibraphone, violin, and violoncello. At end of score: 5/10/61. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Includes typescript instructions for performance (1 leaf), with reversed copy. Assigned publisher's number 6905 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Atlantis c1962., 1 ms. score (19 leaves); 17 x 27 cm. (Box 1, Item 06)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For chamber orchestra. At end of score: Sept. 28 1959. Includes typescript performance instructions (2 leaves; 28 cm.) and mockup in reverse print of title for Peters edition. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6906 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intersection, no. 1 Intersection #1 c1962., 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 14 x 34 cm. (Box 1, Item 07)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. Graphic notation. At end of score: Feb. 1951. Includes two typescript copies of performance instructions (2 leaves; 28-29 cm.), with one extra copy in reverse print. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6907 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intervals Intervals I c1962., 1 ms. score (16 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 08)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For bass-baritone voice, trombone, vibraphone, chimes, antique cymbals, tenor drum, bass drum, and violoncello; without words. At end of score: Sept. 16, 1961. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6908 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Marginal intersection c1962., 1 ms. score (11 leaves); 14 x 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 09)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For orchestra. Graphic notation. At end of score: July 7, 1951. Includes typescript performance instructions (2 leaves; 28 cm.). Leaves 1-2, 3-4, 5-6, 7-8, 9-10 taped together. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6909 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Out of "Last pieces" c1962., 1 ms. score (12 leaves); 25 x 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 10)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For orchestra. Graphic notation. At end of score: 3/61. Includes typescript performance instructions (leaves I-II; 31 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6910 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Out of "Last pieces" [1962], 21 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 11)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum masters). For orchestra. Graphic notation. Assigned publisher's number 6910 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Extensions, no. 1 Extensions 1: for violin and piano c1962., 1 ms. score (17 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 12)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: Nov. 12, 1951. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6911 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Structures, string quartet Structures: for string quartet / [Morton Feldman]. c1962., 1 ms. score (12 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 13)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: March 1951. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6912 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Projection, no. 4 Projection 4: for violin and piano c1959., 1 ms. score (III, 8 leaves); 22 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 14)
    Ms. (Ink, vellum master in the hand of John Cage). Graphic notation. Includes instructions for performance. At end of score: 1-16-51. "Copyright 1959 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of t.p. Assigned publisher's number 6913 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Extensions, no. 4 Extensions 4 c1962., 1 ms. score (21 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 15)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For 3 pianos. At end of score: late summer, 1952 - April 27, 1953. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6914 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intersection, no. 3 Intersection 3: for piano solo c1962., 4 ms. leaves of music; 18 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 16)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Graphic notation. Includes instructions for performance. At end of score: April, 1953. At head of title: For David Tudor. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf t.p. Assigned publisher's number 6915 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, pianos (2) Two pieces for two pianos c1962., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 17)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of piece 1: Nov. 17, 1954; at end of 2nd piece: Nov. 21, 1954. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6916 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, string quartet Three pieces for string quartet c1962., 1 ms. score (19 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 18)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: April 10, 1956. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6917 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, pianos (4) Piece for 4 pianos c1962., 1 ms. score (1 leaf); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 19)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 1957. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6918 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 The Straits of Magellan c1962., 1 ms. score (9 leaves); 20 x 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 20)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For flute, horn, trumpet, amplified guitar, harp, piano, and contrabass. Graphic notation. At end of score: 12/61. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6919 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, clarinet, strings Two pieces for clarinet and string quartet c1962., 1 ms. score (6 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 21)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: April 1961. At head of title: For David Oppenheim. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.), with extra copy. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6920 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 The swallows of Salangan c1962., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 22)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For chorus (SSAATB), 4 flutes, alto flute, 5 trumpets, 2 tubas, 2 vibraphones, 2 pianos, and 7 violoncellos; without words. Includes instructions for performance. At end of score: Oct. 1960. Excerpt from Safe Conduct by Boris Pasternak, source of the title of the work, printed on t.p. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6921 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 The swallows of Salangan [1962], 7 ms. parts; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 23)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum masters). For chorus (SSAATB), 4 flutes, alto flute, 5 trumpets, 2 tubas, 2 vibraphones, 2 pianos, and 7 violoncellos; without words. Includes instructions for performance (1 leaf; 28 cm.). Includes excerpt from Safe Conduct by Boris Pasternak, source of the title of the work (1 leaf; 27 cm.). Parts available only on rental from C.F. Peters. Assigned publisher's number 6921 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Swallows of Salangan. Chorus score The swallows of Salangan / M. Feldman. [1962], 1 ms. chorus score (leaves 2-3); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 24)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For chorus (SSAATB), 4 flutes, alto flute, 5 trumpets, 2 tubas, 2 vibraphones, 2 pianos, and 7 violoncellos; without the accompaniment; without words. Assigned publisher's number 6921a upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intersection, no. 2 Intersection 2: for piano solo c196., IV, 12 ms. leaves of music; 15 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 25)
    Ms. (Ink, vellum master in hand of John Cage). Graphic notation. Includes instructions for performance. At end of score: New York City, August 1951. "To David Tudor"--Leaf II. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of t.p. Assigned publisher's number 6922 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intermissions, no. 1-2 Two intermissions c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 26)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For piano. At end of score: 1950. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6923 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1952) Piano piece 1952 c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 27)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6924 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Extensions, no. 3 Extensions 3 c1962., 4 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 28)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For piano. At end of score: 1952. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6925 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Ixion c1962., 1 ms. score (19 leaves); 12 x 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 29)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Graphic notation. Caption title. For 3 flutes, clarinet, horn, trumpet, trombone, piano, violoncellos (3 to 7), and double basses (2 to 4). Commissioned by Merce Cunnigham for his dance "Summer Space." At end of score: August, 1958. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 24 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6926 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Ixion / M. Feldman. c1963., 10 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 30)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum masters). Caption title. For 3 flutes, clarinet, horn, trumpet, trombone, piano, violoncellos (3 to 7), and double basses (2 to 4). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6926 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Ixion; arr. Ixion c1963., 1 ms. score (5 leaves); 23 x 29 cm. (Box 1, Item 31)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For two pianos; originally for 10 unspecified instruments. Caption title. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. "Peters #6926A"--Bottom of leaf 1.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Journey to the end of the night c1963., 1 ms. score (12 leaves); 39 cm. (Box 1, Item 32)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For high voice, flute, clarinet, bass clarinet, and bassoon.At end of score: 1947. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6927 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Journey to the end of the night c1963., 4 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 33)
    Ms. (Ink, vellum masters, copyist's hand). For soprano, flute, bassoon, clarinet, and bass clarinet; instrumental parts only included. Title from caption of flute part. "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6927a upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intermission, no. 6 Intermission 6: for one or two pianos c1963., 1 ms. leaf of music; 30 cm. (Box 1, Item 34)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. Chance composition. At end of score: 1953. Includes two typescript copies of performance instructions (1 leaf ea.; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1963 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6928 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Eleven instruments c1962., 1 ms. score (21 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 35)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: Dec. 1953. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6929 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, winds, strings Two pieces for six instruments c1964., 1 ms. score (9 leaves); 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 36)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For flute, alto flute, horn, trumpet, violin, and violoncello. At end of score: Sept. 23, 1956. "Copyright 1964 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., N.Y. 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6930 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1956a) Piano piece 1956 A c1961., 2 ms. leaves of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Item 37)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At head of title: For Cynthia. "Copyright 1961 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. South, New York, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6931 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1956b) Piano piece 1956 B c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 38)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6932 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Structures, orchestra Structures: for orchestra c1962., 1 ms. score (15 leaves); 39 cm. (Box 1, Item 39)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 1960-1962. Typed title pasted over ms. title in caption. Includes typescript explanatory note by the composer (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Avenue South, New York, N.Y."--Label pasted on bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6934 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Structures, orchestra Structures: for orchestra [1962], 30 ms. parts; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 40)
    Ms. (Ink, vellum masters, copyist's hand). Title from caption of 1st flute part. Includes typescript explanatory note by the composer (1 leaf; 28 cm.). Assigned publisher's number 6934 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Intermission, no. 5 Intermission 5 c1962., 3 ms. leaves of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Item 41)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For piano. At end of score: 1952. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corp., 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6935 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Songs to e.e. cummings 4 songs to e.e. cummings: voice, cello, piano c1962., 1 ms. score (4 leaves); 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 42)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: 1951. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6936 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1954) Three pieces for piano c1962., 4 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 43)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of each mvt., respectively: 3-12-54 -- Feb. '54 -- Oct. '54. "Copyright 1962 by C. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6937 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Two instruments: horn and cello c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 44)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master; t.p. in copyist's hand). At end of score: 5.18.58. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.); additional performance instructions on t.p. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6938 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Two pianos c1962., 2 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 45)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. The two pianists play from identical parts; time values are left to the discretion of the performers. At end of score: 12-5-57. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6939 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Projection, no. 2 Projection 2 c1962., 1 ms. score (9 leaves); 17 x 28 cm. (Box 1, Item 46)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. For flute, trumpet, violin, violoncello, and piano. Graphic notation. At end of score: Jan. 3, 1951. Includes typescript performance instructions (1 leaf; 28 cm.). "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6940 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Last pieces c1962., 4 ms. leaves of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 47)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). For piano. Caption title. At end of each movement, respectively: 3.25.59, 3.29.59, 3.30.59, 4.3.59. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Cover folder for Peters publication inserted. Assigned publisher's number 6941 upon publication by Peters.
  - Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 Pieces, piano (1955) Piano piece 1955 c1962., 1 ms. leaf of music; 36 cm. (Box 1, Item 48)
    Holograph (Ink, vellum master). Caption title. At end of score: Jan. 4, 1955. "Copyright 1962 by C.F. Peters Corporation, 373 Park Ave. So., New York 16, N.Y."--Bottom of leaf 1. Assigned publisher's number 6942 upon publication by Peters.